Austin Osorio

| contact@austinosor.io California | 209-

Github austinoso | Blog | austinosor.io

SUMMARY

Full-Stack web developer with experience in Ruby and JavaScript frameworks. Self-employment has enabled me to work effectively against deadlines as well as hone my communication skills with clientele. I've always been the sort of person who loves diving into details. I'm naturally good at making sense of seemingly disconnected data points and creating clarity and certainty from data. Strong attention to detail, which translates to writing clean and elegant code.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Ruby, JavaScript, Rails, Node, Express, React, Google Firebase, WordPress, SQLite, PostgreSQL, MongoDB, Linux, and Adobe Suite Software Including: Illustrator, Dreamweaver, Photoshop, After Effects, and XD.

TECHNICAL PROJECTS

Sealed - Github Frontend Github Backend | Live Demo | Demo

Flatiron School - Student

Messaging application featuring single-use "burner" chats. Allowing users to quickly delete all message history at the single click of a button.

- Utilized Actioncable and Redis to take advantage of web sockets to seamlessly transmit data to the frontend live.
- Implemented user interface with React and react-bootstrap for styling.
- Utilized JSON Web Tokens and localStorage to store encrypted user information client-side.

Corona Files - Github Frontend Github Backend | Demo

Flatiron School - Student

Web application with a voting system similar to Reddit's upvotes and downvotes helps filter Corona Virus news.

- Implemented user interface with React and react-bootstrap for styling.
- Utilized JSON Web Tokens and localStorage to store encrypted user information client-side.
- Utilized the Google Maps API and react-geocode to add locations to news sources.

EXPERIENCE

Self Employed

Software Development

May 2020 - Present

Stockton, CA

- Delivered software products such as, front-end web applications, back-end API's, and desktop applications.
- Building web applications with React, Firebase, Node, Express, SQL, and NoSQL Databases.
- Gathered technical specifications from clients and implemented change requests.
- Managed multiple projects, optimized delivery schedules to meet client expectations and deadlines.

Self Employed Stockton, CA Web Design Jan 2018 - Jan 2020

- Delivered web design projects for business retail, gaming, and academic services.
- Building web pages with WordPress and other design projects with Illustrator, Photoshop, and After Effects.
- Gathered technical specifications from clients and implemented change requests and design enchantments.
- Managed multiple projects, optimized delivery schedules to meet client expectations and deadlines.

EDUCATION

Flatiron School San Francisco, CA Jan 2020 - May 2020

Full Stack Web Development, Ruby on Rails and JavaScript program